freedomworks.org 2012-09-20

# Privacy Policy | FreedomWorks

_(Last Updated: February 9, 2009)_

#### Policy Statement

FreedomWorks is dedicated to protecting the privacy of our online members and donors. We’ve developed these easy-to-understand Privacy Practices from guidelines established by leading privacy organizations, including eTrust.com and the Better Business Bureau.

#### Gathering and Usage of Information

FreedomWorks collects personal information from you on a voluntary basis and we don’t require it to obtain non-membership access to FreedomWorks.org. The types of personal information we collect may include your name, mailing address, email address, and phone number.

We do not sell or share your email address or phone number with any third parties, (other than information technology vendors we use to manage systems such as our database and email delivery). Some activities on FreedomWorks.org explicitly involve sharing your personal information with a third party, such as your elected officials. If you sign a petition or similar call to action that has the express purpose of sending emails or petitions to Congress, the media, or similar, we will share your personal information with the target of the call to action.

On some occasions, we will make our membership postal mailing list available to allied organizations for the purpose of sending direct mail.

#### Opt-Out

FreedomWorks maintains several opt-out and opt-in email lists, including our weekly newsletter and special state and issue updates. We give you control over these subscriptions and at any time you may “opt-out” and remove your e-mail address from our files. There is an “unsubscribe” process detailed at the bottom of every email, or you can contact us at http://www.freedomworks.org/contact to be removed from our email list.

#### Cookies

FreedomWorks.org uses “cookie” technology to obtain non-personal information from our online visitors, such as browser/computer type, number of visitors, IP address, and site usage. We don’t use cookies to extract personal information.

#### Links

Although FreedomWorks.org contains links to other sites, FreedomWorks does not necessarily advocate, support or condone the privacy practices or content of these various Web sites.

#### Public Forums

At FreedomWorks.org, you have the opportunity to participate in various online contests, comment boards, and discussions. Please remember that any information that you disclose in our chat rooms, forums, message boards, or new groups becomes public information. Exercise caution when deciding to disclose any of your personal information, and please do not disclose direct contact information such as your mailing address, phone number, or email address.

#### Security

FreedomWorks has taken steps to make all information received from our online visitors as secure as possible against unauthorized access and use. All information is protected by our security measures, which are periodically reviewed.

#### Ongoing Privacy Efforts

FreedomWorks approaches our Internet communications with respect for and commitment to individual privacy rights and concerns. We support active self-regulation of this environment to ensure that responsible organizations maintain the right to use all communications media to interact with the public. As the Internet evolves, our policy will continue to develop. Please check back periodically to see changes and additions.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or the FreedomWorks Web Site, please contact us by calling (202) 783-3870 or contact us online.
